Total found: 46
Line 108 | Section 21 (*Indigent party*) | assessed and collected by the clerk of court. If payment is not made within the time fixed by the co
Line 316 | Section 5 (*No amendment necessary to conform to or authorize presentation of evidence*) | be treated in all respects as if they had been raised in the pleadings. No amendment of such pleadin
Line 407 | Section 10 (*Presumptive service*) | the case is pending, or at least thirty (30) calendar days if the addressee is from outside the judi
Line 495 | Section 6 (*Substituted service*) | corporation, or its chief security officer in charge of the community or the building where the defe
Line 537 | Section 17 (*Extraterritorial service*) | newspaper of general circulation in such places and for such time as the court may order, in which c
Line 575 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | a) Motion for the issuance of an alias summons;
Line 576 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | b) Motion for extension to file answer;
Line 577 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | c) Motion for postponement;
Line 578 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | d) Motion for the issuance of a writ of execution;
Line 579 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | e) Motion for the issuance of an alias writ of execution;
Line 580 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | f) Motion for the issuance of a writ of possession;
Line 581 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | g) Motion for the issuance of an order directing the sheriff to execute the final certificate of sal
Line 582 | Section 4 (*Non-litigious motions*) | h) Other similar motions.
Line 645 | Section 1 (*Dismissal upon notice by plaintiff*) | the merits when filed by a plaintiff who has once dismissed in a competent court an action based on 
Line 675 | Section 2 (*Nature and purpose*) | i. For testimonial evidence, by giving the name or position and the nature of the testimony of the p
Line 676 | Section 2 (*Nature and purpose*) | ii. For documentary evidence and other object evidence, by giving a particular description of the ev
Line 817 | Section 2 (*Scope of examination*) | the subject of the pending action, whether relating to the claim or defense of any other party, incl
Line 873 | Section 19 (*Submission to witness; changes; signing*) | statement of the reasons given by the witness for making them. The deposition shall then be signed b
Line 889 | Section 26 (*Officers to take responses and prepare record*) | the notice, who shall proceed promptly, in the manner provided by Sections 17, 19 and 20 of this Rul
Line 979 | Section 3 (*Other consequences*) | order under Rule 27 to produce any document or other thing for inspection, copying, or photographing
Line 1001 | Section 1 (*Schedule of trial*) | i. The initial presentation of plaintiff's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calendar
Line 1003 | Section 1 (*Schedule of trial*) | ii. The initial presentation of defendant's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calenda
Line 1005 | Section 1 (*Schedule of trial*) | iii. The period for the presentation of evidence on the third (fourth, etc.)-party claim, countercla
Line 1007 | Section 1 (*Schedule of trial*) | iv. If deemed necessary, the court shall set the presentation of the parties' respective rebuttal ev
Line 1242 | Section 9 (*Execution of judgments for money, how enforced*) | to which the judgment obligor is entitled. The garnishment shall cover only such amount as will sati
Line 1322 | Section 20 (*Refusal of purchaser to pay) | purchaser to pay into the court the amount of such loss, with costs, and may punish him for contempt
Line 1370 | Section 34 (*Recovery of price if sale not effective; revival of judgment*) | judgment obligor. The judgment so revived shall have the same force and effect as an original judgme
Line 1382 | Section 39 (*Obligor may pay execution against obligee*) | execution the amount of his debt or so much thereof as may be necessary to satisfy the judgment, in 
Line 1555 | Section 1 (*Scope*) | of Investments, Construction Industry Arbitration Commission, and voluntary arbitrators authorized b
Line 1709 | Section 4 (*Filing and contents of petition*) | divisions thereof, or any other tribunal or agency; if there is such other action or proceeding, he 
Line 1851 | Section 2 (*Rules applicable*) | a) All references in said Rules to the Court of Appeals shall be understood to also apply to the Sup
Line 1852 | Section 2 (*Rules applicable*) | b) The portions of said Rules dealing strictly with and specifically intended for appealed cases in 
Line 1853 | Section 2 (*Rules applicable*) | c) Eighteen (18) clearly legible copies of the petition shall be filed, together with proof of servi
Line 1908 | Section 7 (*Attachment of real and personal property; recording thereof*) | by the certificate of title, a description sufficiently accurate for the identification of the land 
Line 1952 | Section 16 (*Balance due collected upon an execution; excess delivered to judgment obligor*) | ordinary execution. Whenever the judgment shall have been paid, the sheriff, upon reasonable demand,
Line 1970 | Section 1 (*Preliminary injunction defined; classes*) | or a person to refrain from a particular act or acts. It may also require the performance of a parti
Line 2003 | Section 6 (*Grounds for objection to, or for motion of dissolution of, injunction or restraining order*) | by the court conditioned that he will pay all damages which the applicant may suffer by the denial o
Line 2107 | Section 4 (*Motion to dismiss) | file his answer within the remaining period, but which shall not be less than five (5) days in any e
Line 2186 | Section 5 (*Respondents and costs in certain cases*) | petitioner shall be against the private respondents only, and not against the judge, court, quasi-ju
Line 2259 | Section 4 (*Order of expropriation) | the court may issue an order of expropriation declaring that the plaintiff has a lawful right to tak
Line 2273 | Section 7 (*Report by commissioners and judgment thereupon*) | that they are allowed ten (10) days within which to file objections to the findings of the report, i
Line 2287 | Section 13 (*Recording judgment, and its effect*) | property is situated, and its effect shall be to vest in the plaintiff the title to the real estate 
Line 2303 | Section 4 (*Disposition of proceeds of sale*) | mortgage, and when there shall be any balance or residue, after paying off the mortgage debt due, th
Line 2335 | Section 7 (*Action of the court upon commissioners' report*) | and render such judgment as shall effectuate a fair and just partition of the real estate, or of its
Line 2365 | Section 7 (*Effect of failure to answer*) | court may in its discretion reduce the amount of damages and attorney's fees claimed for being exces
Line 2431 | Section 19 (*Immediate execution of judgment; how to stay same*) | deprived of the lawful possession of land or building pending the appeal by virtue of the execution 
