Total Sections with enumeration: 140

--- Top Targets for Cascading Indentation ---
[Section 3.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Cases governed. ù These Rules shall govern the procedure to be observed in actions, civil or crimina...
---------------
[Section 5.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Joinder of causes of action. ù A party may in one pleading assert, in the alternative or otherwise, ...
---------------
[Section 4.] Types: alpha
  Sample: When Rule not applicable. ù This Rule shall not apply-  (a) In those cases where a specific rule or ...
---------------
[Section 5.] Types: alpha
  Sample: *Defenses.* û Defenses may either be negative or affirmative.  (a) A negative defense is the specifi...
---------------
[Section 2.] Types: alpha
  Sample: The body. ù The body of the pleading sets forth its designation, the allegations of the party's clai...
---------------
[Section 3.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Signature and address. ù (a) Every pleading and other written submissions to the court must be signe...
---------------
[Section 4.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Verification. ù Except when otherwise specifically required by law or rule, pleadings need not be un...
---------------
[Section 6.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Contents. ù Every pleading stating a party's claims or defenses shall, in addition to those mandated...
---------------
[Section 12.] Types: alpha, numeric
  Sample: Affirmative defenses. ù (a) A defendant shall raise his or her affirmative defenses in his or her an...
---------------
[Section 3.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Default; declaration of. ù If the defending party fails to answer within the time allowed therefor, ...
---------------
[Section 3.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Manner of filing. ù The filing of pleadings and other court submissions shall be made by:  (a) Submi...
---------------
[Section 14.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Conventional service or filing of orders, pleadings and other documents. ù Notwithstanding the foreg...
---------------
[Section 16.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Proof of filing. ù The filing of a pleading or any other court submission shall be proved by its exi...
---------------
[Section 17.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Proof of service. ù Proof of personal service shall consist of a written admission of the party serv...
---------------
[Section 2.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Contents. ù The summons shall be directed to the defendant, signed by the clerk of court under seal,...
---------------
[Section 6.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Substituted service. ù If, for justifiable causes, the defendant cannot be served personally after a...
---------------
[Section 14.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Service upon foreign private juridical entities. ù When the defendant is a foreign private juridical...
---------------
[Section 5.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Litigious motions. ù (a) Litigious motions include:  1) Motion for bill of particulars;  ### Rule 15...
---------------
[Section 12.] Types: alpha
  Sample: Prohibited motions. ù The following motions shall not be allowed:  (a) Motion to dismiss except on t...
---------------
[Section 2.] Types: alpha, numeric
  Sample: Nature and purpose. ù The pre-trial is mandatory and should be terminated promptly. The court shall ...
---------------
