REPORT_START
LINE: 108
PREV: Any adverse party may contest the grant of such authority at any time before judgment is rendered by the trial court. If the court should determine after hearing that the party declared as an indigent is in fact a person with sufficient income or property, the proper docket and other lawful fees shall be
THIS: assessed and collected by the clerk of court. If payment is not made within the time fixed by the court, execution shall issue or the payment thereof, without prejudice to such other sanctions as the court may impose. (22a)
--------------------
LINE: 316
PREV: Section 5. *No amendment necessary to conform to or authorize presentation of evidence*. ù When issues not raised by the pleadings are tried with the express or implied consent of the parties, they shall
THIS: be treated in all respects as if they had been raised in the pleadings. No amendment of such pleadings deemed amended is necessary to cause them to conform to the evidence. (5a)
--------------------
LINE: 407
PREV: Section 10. *Presumptive service*. ù There shall be presumptive notice to a party of a court setting if such notice appears on the records to have been mailed at least twenty (20) calendar days prior to the scheduled date of hearing and if the addressee is from within the same judicial region of the court where
THIS: the case is pending, or at least thirty (30) calendar days if the addressee is from outside the judicial region. (n)
--------------------
LINE: 495
PREV: (c) By leaving copies of the summons, if refused entry upon making his or her authority and purpose known, with any of the officers of the homeowners' association or condominium
THIS: corporation, or its chief security officer in charge of the community or the building where the defendant may be found; and
--------------------
LINE: 537
PREV: Section 17. *Extraterritorial service*. ù When the defendant does not reside and is not found in the Philippines, and the action affects the personal status of the plaintiff or relates to, or the subject of which is, property within the Philippines, in which the defendant has or claims a lien or interest, actual or contingent, or in which the relief demanded consists, wholly or in part, in excluding the defendant from any interest therein, or the property of the defendant has been attached within the Philippines, service may, by leave of court, be effected out of the Philippines by personal service as under Section 5; or as provided for in international conventions to which the Philippines is a party; or by publication in a
THIS: newspaper of general circulation in such places and for such time as the court may order, in which case a copy of the summons and order of the court shall be sent by registered mail to the last known address of the defendant, or in any other manner the court may deem sufficient. Any order granting such leave shall specify a reasonable time, which shall not be less than sixty (60) calendar days after notice, within which the defendant must answer. (15a)
--------------------
LINE: 645
PREV: Section 1. *Dismissal upon notice by plaintiff*. ù A complaint may be dismissed by the plaintiff by filing a notice of dismissal at any time before service of the answer or of a motion for summary judgment. Upon such notice being filed, the court shall issue an order confirming the dismissal. Unless otherwise stated in the notice, the dismissal is without prejudice, except that a notice operates as an adjudication upon
THIS: the merits when filed by a plaintiff who has once dismissed in a competent court an action based on or including the same claim. (1)
--------------------
LINE: 675
PREV: 4. Reserve evidence not available at the pre-trial, but only in the following manner:
THIS: i. For testimonial evidence, by giving the name or position and the nature of the testimony of the proposed witness;
--------------------
LINE: 676
PREV: i. For testimonial evidence, by giving the name or position and the nature of the testimony of the proposed witness;
THIS: ii. For documentary evidence and other object evidence, by giving a particular description of the evidence.
--------------------
LINE: 817
PREV: Section 2. *Scope of examination*. ù Unless otherwise ordered by the court as provided by Section 16 or 18 of this Rule, the deponent may be examined regarding any matter, not privileged, which is relevant to
THIS: the subject of the pending action, whether relating to the claim or defense of any other party, including the existence, description, nature, custody, condition, and location of any books, documents, or other tangible things and the identity and location of persons having knowledge of relevant facts. (2)
--------------------
LINE: 873
PREV: Section 19. *Submission to witness; changes; signing*. ù When the testimony is fully transcribed, the deposition shall be submitted to the witness for examination and shall be read to or by him or her, unless such examination and reading are waived by the witness and by the parties. Any changes in form or substance which the witness desires to make shall be entered upon the deposition by the officer with a
THIS: statement of the reasons given by the witness for making them. The deposition shall then be signed by the witness, unless the parties by stipulation waive the signing or the witness is ill or cannot be found or refuses to sign. If the deposition is not signed by the witness, the officer shall sign it and state on the record the fact of the waiver or of the illness or absence of the witness or the fact of the refusal to sign together with the reason given therefor, if any, and the deposition may then be used as fully as though signed, unless on a motion to suppress under Section 29(f) of this Rule, the court holds that the reasons given for the refusal to sign require rejection of the deposition in whole or in part. (19a)
--------------------
LINE: 889
PREV: Section 26. *Officers to take responses and prepare record*. ù A copy of the notice and copies of all interrogatories served shall be delivered by the party taking the deposition to the officer designated in
THIS: the notice, who shall proceed promptly, in the manner provided by Sections 17, 19 and 20 of this Rule, to take the testimony of the witness in response to the interrogatories and to prepare, certify, and file or mail the deposition, attaching thereto the copy of the notice and the interrogatories received by him or her. (26a)
--------------------
LINE: 979
PREV: Section 3. *Other consequences*. ù If any party or an officer or managing agent of a party refuses to obey an order made under Section 1 of this Rule requiring him or her to answer designated questions, or an
THIS: order under Rule 27 to produce any document or other thing for inspection, copying, or photographing or to permit it to be done, or to permit entry upon land or other property, or an order made under Rule 28 requiring him or her to submit to a physical or mental examination, the court may make such orders in regard to the refusal as are just, and among others the following:
--------------------
LINE: 1001
PREV: (a) The schedule of the trial dates, for both plaintiff and defendant, shall be continuous and within the following periods:
THIS: i. The initial presentation of plaintiff's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calendar days after the termination of the pre-trial conference. Plaintiff shall be allowed to present its evidence within a period of three (3) months or ninety (90) calendar days which shall include the date of the judicial dispute resolution, if necessary;
--------------------
LINE: 1003
PREV: i. The initial presentation of plaintiff's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calendar days after the termination of the pre-trial conference. Plaintiff shall be allowed to present its evidence within a period of three (3) months or ninety (90) calendar days which shall include the date of the judicial dispute resolution, if necessary;
THIS: ii. The initial presentation of defendant's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calendar days after the court's ruling on plaintiff's formal offer of evidence. The defendant shall be allowed to present its evidence within a period of three (3) months or ninety (90) calendar days;
--------------------
LINE: 1005
PREV: ii. The initial presentation of defendant's evidence shall be set not later than thirty (30) calendar days after the court's ruling on plaintiff's formal offer of evidence. The defendant shall be allowed to present its evidence within a period of three (3) months or ninety (90) calendar days;
THIS: iii. The period for the presentation of evidence on the third (fourth, etc.)-party claim, counterclaim or cross-claim shall be determined by the court, the total of which shall in no case exceed ninety (90) calendar days; and
--------------------
LINE: 1007
PREV: iii. The period for the presentation of evidence on the third (fourth, etc.)-party claim, counterclaim or cross-claim shall be determined by the court, the total of which shall in no case exceed ninety (90) calendar days; and
THIS: iv. If deemed necessary, the court shall set the presentation of the parties' respective rebuttal evidence, which shall be completed within a period of thirty (30) calendar days.
--------------------
LINE: 1242
PREV: (c) Garnishment of debts and credits. û The officer may levy on debts due the judgment obligor and other credits, including bank deposits, financial interests, royalties, commissions and other personal property not capable of manual delivery in the possession or control of third parties. Levy shall be made by serving notice upon the person owing such debts or having in his possession or control such credits
THIS: to which the judgment obligor is entitled. The garnishment shall cover only such amount as will satisfy the judgment and all lawful fees.
--------------------
LINE: 1322
PREV: Section 20. *Refusal of purchaser to pay.* û If a purchaser refuses to pay the amount bid by him for property struck off to him at a sale under execution, the officer may again sell the property to the highest bidder and shall not be responsible for any loss occasioned thereby; but the court may order the refusing
THIS: purchaser to pay into the court the amount of such loss, with costs, and may punish him for contempt if he disobeys the order. The amount of such payment shall be for the benefit of the person entitled to the proceeds of the execution, unless the execution has been fully satisfied, in which event such proceeds shall be for the benefit of the judgment obligor. The officer may thereafter reject any subsequent bid of such purchaser who refuses to pay. (22a)
--------------------
LINE: 1370
PREV: Section 34. *Recovery of price if sale not effective; revival of judgment*. ù If the purchaser of real property sold on execution, or his successor in interest, fails to recover the possession thereof, or is evicted therefrom, in consequence of irregularities in the proceedings concerning the sale, or because the judgment has been reversed or set aside, or because the property sold was exempt from execution, or because a third person has vindicated his claim to the property, he may on motion in the same action or in a separate action recover from the judgment obligee the price paid, with interest, or so much thereof as has not been delivered to the judgment obligor; or he may, on motion, have the original judgment revived in his name for the whole price with interest, or so much thereof as has been delivered to the
THIS: judgment obligor. The judgment so revived shall have the same force and effect as an original judgment would have as of the date of the revival and no more. (36a)
--------------------
LINE: 1382
PREV: Section 39. *Obligor may pay execution against obligee*. ù After a writ of execution against property has been issued, a person indebted to the judgment obligor may pay to the sheriff holding the writ of
THIS: execution the amount of his debt or so much thereof as may be necessary to satisfy the judgment, in the manner prescribed in section 9 of this Rule, and the sheriff's receipt shall be a sufficient discharge for the amount so paid or directed to be credited by the judgment obligee on the execution. (41a)
--------------------
LINE: 1555
PREV: Section 1. *Scope*. ù This Rule shall apply to appeals from judgments or final orders of the Court of Tax Appeals and from awards, judgments, final orders or resolutions of or authorized by any quasi-judicial agency in the exercise of its quasi-judicial functions. Among these agencies are the Civil Service Commission, Central Board of Assessment Appeals, Securities and Exchange Commission, Office of the President, Land Registration Authority, Social Security Commission, Civil Aeronautics Board, Bureau of Patents, Trademarks and Technology Transfer, National Electrification Administration, Energy Regulatory Board, National Telecommunications Commission, Department of Agrarian Reform under Republic Act No. 6657, Government Service Insurance System, Employees Compensation Commission, Agricultural Inventions Board, Insurance Commission, Philippine Atomic Energy Commission, Board
THIS: of Investments, Construction Industry Arbitration Commission, and voluntary arbitrators authorized by law. (n)
--------------------
LINE: 1709
PREV: The petitioner shall also submit together with the petition affidavits of witnesses or documents supporting the cause of action or defense and a sworn certification that he has not theretofore commenced any other action involving the same issues in the Supreme Court, the Court of Appeals or different
THIS: divisions thereof, or any other tribunal or agency; if there is such other action or proceeding, he must state the status of the same, and if he should thereafter learn that a similar action or proceeding has been filed or is pending before the Supreme Court, the Court of Appeals, or different divisions thereof, or any other tribunal or agency, he undertakes to promptly inform the aforesaid courts and other tribunal or agency thereof within five (5) days therefrom. (n)
--------------------
LINE: 1908
PREV: The registrar of deeds must index attachments filed under this section in the names of the applicant, the adverse party, or the person by whom the property is held or in whose name it stands in the records. If the attachment is not claimed on the entire area of the land covered
THIS: by the certificate of title, a description sufficiently accurate for the identification of the land or interest to be affected shall be included in the registration of such attachment;
--------------------
LINE: 1952
PREV: Section 16. *Balance due collected upon an execution; excess delivered to judgment obligor*. ù If after realizing upon all the property attached, including the proceeds of any debts or credits collected, and applying the proceeds to the satisfaction of the judgment, less the expenses of proceedings upon the judgment, any balance shall remain due, the sheriff must proceed to collect such balance as upon
THIS: ordinary execution. Whenever the judgment shall have been paid, the sheriff, upon reasonable demand, must return to the judgment obligor the attached property remaining in his hands, and any proceeds of the sale of the property attached not applied to the judgment. (16a)
--------------------
LINE: 1970
PREV: Section 1. *Preliminary injunction defined; classes*. ù A preliminary injunction is an order granted at any stage of an action or proceeding prior to the judgment or final order, requiring a party or a court, agency
THIS: or a person to refrain from a particular act or acts. It may also require the performance of a particular act or acts, in which case it shall be known as a preliminary mandatory injunction. (1a)
--------------------
LINE: 2003
PREV: Section 6. *Grounds for objection to, or for motion of dissolution of, injunction or restraining order*. ù The application for injunction or restraining order may be denied, upon a showing of its insufficiency. The injunction or restraining order may also be denied, or, if granted, may be dissolved, on other grounds upon affidavits of the party or person enjoined, which may be opposed by the applicant also by affidavits. It may further be denied, or, if granted, may be dissolved, if it appears after hearing that although the applicant is entitled to the injunction or restraining order, the issuance or continuance thereof, as the case may be, would cause irreparable damage to the party or person enjoined while the applicant can be fully compensated for such damages as he may suffer, and the former files a bond in an amount fixed
THIS: by the court conditioned that he will pay all damages which the applicant may suffer by the denial or the dissolution of the injunction or restraining order. If it appears that the extent of the preliminary injunction or restraining order granted is too great, it may be modified. (6a)
--------------------
LINE: 2107
PREV: Section 4. *Motion to dismiss.* û Within the time for filing an answer, each claimant may file a motion to dismiss on the ground of impropriety of the interpleader action or on other appropriate grounds specified in Rule 16. The period to file the answer shall be tolled and if the motion is denied, the movant may
THIS: file his answer within the remaining period, but which shall not be less than five (5) days in any event, reckoned from notice of denial. (n)
--------------------
LINE: 2186
PREV: Section 5. *Respondents and costs in certain cases*. ù When the petition filed relates to the acts or omissions of a judge, court, quasi-judicial agency, tribunal, corporation, board, officer or person, the petitioner shall join, as private respondent or respondents with such public respondent or respondents, the person or persons interested in sustaining the proceedings in the court; and it shall be the duty of such private respondents to appear and defend, both in his or their own behalf and in behalf of the public respondent or respondents affected by the proceedings, and the costs awarded in such proceedings in favor of the
THIS: petitioner shall be against the private respondents only, and not against the judge, court, quasi-judicial agency, tribunal, corporation, board, officer or person impleaded as public respondent or respondents.
--------------------
LINE: 2259
PREV: EXPROPRIATION
THIS: the court may issue an order of expropriation declaring that the plaintiff has a lawful right to take the property sought to be expropriated, for the public use or purpose described in the complaint, upon the payment of just compensation to be determined as of the date of the taking of the property or the filing of the complaint, whichever came first.
--------------------
LINE: 2273
PREV: Section 7. *Report by commissioners and judgment thereupon*. ù The court may order the commissioners to report when any particular portion of the real estate shall have been passed upon by them, and may render judgment upon such partial report, and direct the commissioners to proceed with their work as to subsequent portions of the property sought to be expropriated, and may from time to time so deal with such property. The commissioners shall make a full and accurate report to the court of all their proceedings, and such proceedings shall not be effectual until the court shall have accepted their report and rendered judgment in accordance with their recommendations. Except as otherwise expressly ordered by the court, such report shall be filed within sixty (60) days from the date the commissioners were notified of their appointment, which time may be extended in the discretion of the court. Upon the filing of such report, the clerk of the court shall serve copies thereof on all interested parties, with notice
THIS: that they are allowed ten (10) days within which to file objections to the findings of the report, if they so desire. (7a)
--------------------
LINE: 2287
PREV: Section 13. *Recording judgment, and its effect*. ù The judgment entered in expropriation proceedings shall state definitely, by an adequate description, the particular property or interest therein expropriated, and the nature of the public use or purpose for which it is expropriated. When real estate is expropriated, a certified copy of such judgment shall be recorded in the registry of deeds of the place in which the
THIS: property is situated, and its effect shall be to vest in the plaintiff the title to the real estate so described for such public use or purpose. (13a)
--------------------
LINE: 2303
PREV: Section 4. *Disposition of proceeds of sale*. ù The amount realized from the foreclosure sale of the mortgaged property shall, after deducting the costs of the sale, be paid to the person foreclosing the
THIS: mortgage, and when there shall be any balance or residue, after paying off the mortgage debt due, the same shall be paid to junior encumbrancers in the order of their priority, to be ascertained by the court, or if there be no such encumbrancers or there be a balance or residue after payment to them, then to the mortgagor or his duly authorized agent, or to the person entitled to it. (4a)
--------------------
LINE: 2335
PREV: Section 7. *Action of the court upon commissioners' report*. ù Upon the expiration of the period of ten (10) days referred to in the preceding section, or even before the expiration of such period but after the interested parties have filed their objections to the report or their statement of agreement therewith, the court may, upon hearing, accept the report and render judgment in accordance therewith; or, for cause shown, recommit the same to the commissioners for further report of facts; or set aside the report and appoint new commissioners; or accept the report in part and reject it in part; and may make such order
THIS: and render such judgment as shall effectuate a fair and just partition of the real estate, or of its value, if assigned or sold as above provided, between the several owners thereof. (7)
--------------------
LINE: 2365
PREV: Section 7. *Effect of failure to answer*. ù Should the defendant fail to answer the complaint within the period above provided, the court, motu proprio or on motion of the plaintiff, shall render judgment as may be warranted by the facts alleged in the complaint and limited to what is prayed for therein. The
THIS: court may in its discretion reduce the amount of damages and attorney's fees claimed for being excessive or otherwise unconscionable, without prejudice to the applicability of section 3 (c), Rule 9 if there are two or more defendants. (6, RSP)
--------------------
LINE: 2431
PREV: After the case is decided by the Regional Trial Court, any money paid to the court by the defendant for purposes of the stay of execution shall be disposed of in accordance with the provisions of the judgment of the Regional Trial Court. In any case wherein it appears that the defendant has been
THIS: deprived of the lawful possession of land or building pending the appeal by virtue of the execution of the judgment of the Municipal Trial Court, damages for such deprivation of possession and restoration of possession may be allowed the defendant in the judgment of the Regional Trial Court disposing of the appeal. (8a)
--------------------
REPORT_END
